<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE feature_key_file [
   <!ELEMENT feature_key_file (comments, feature+)>
   <!ELEMENT comments (#PCDATA)>
   <!ELEMENT feature (name, description?, is_sequential, parallel_dimensions)>
   <!ELEMENT name (#PCDATA)>
   <!ELEMENT description (#PCDATA)>
   <!ELEMENT is_sequential (#PCDATA)>
   <!ELEMENT parallel_dimensions (#PCDATA)>
]>

<feature_key_file>

   <comments></comments>

   <feature>
      <name>Range</name>
      <description>Difference in semitones between the highest and lowest pitches.</description>
      <is_sequential>true</is_sequential>
      <parallel_dimensions>1</parallel_dimensions>
   </feature>

   <feature>
      <name>Mean Pitch</name>
      <description>Mean MIDI pitch value, averaged across all pitched notes in the piece. Set to 0 if there are no pitched notes.</description>
      <is_sequential>true</is_sequential>
      <parallel_dimensions>1</parallel_dimensions>
   </feature>

   <feature>
      <name>Major or Minor</name>
      <description>Whether the piece is major or minor, as indicated by the first encountered major/minor metadata tag in the piece. Set to 0 if the metadata indicates that the piece is major, or set to 1 if the metadata indicates that it is minor. Defaults to 0 if the key signature is unknown.</description>
      <is_sequential>true</is_sequential>
      <parallel_dimensions>1</parallel_dimensions>
   </feature>

   <feature>
      <name>Chromatic Motion</name>
      <description>Fraction of melodic intervals that correspond to a semitone.</description>
      <is_sequential>true</is_sequential>
      <parallel_dimensions>1</parallel_dimensions>
   </feature>

   <feature>
      <name>Direction of Melodic Motion</name>
      <description>Fraction of melodic intervals that are rising in pitch. Set to zero if no rising or falling melodic intervals are found.</description>
      <is_sequential>true</is_sequential>
      <parallel_dimensions>1</parallel_dimensions>
   </feature>

   <feature>
      <name>Melodic Pitch Variety</name>
      <description>Average number of notes that go by in a MIDI channel before a note's pitch is repeated (including the repeated note itself). This is calculated across each channel individually before being combined. Notes that occur simultaneously on the same MIDI tick are only counted as one note for the purpose of this calculation. Notes that do not recur after 16 notes in the same channel are not included in this calculation. Set to 0 if there are no qualifying repeated notes in the piece.</description>
      <is_sequential>true</is_sequential>
      <parallel_dimensions>1</parallel_dimensions>
   </feature>

   <feature>
      <name>Note Density</name>
      <description>Average number of notes per second. Takes into account all notes in all voices, including both pitched and unpitched notes.</description>
      <is_sequential>true</is_sequential>
      <parallel_dimensions>1</parallel_dimensions>
   </feature>

   <feature>
      <name>Average Note Duration</name>
      <description>Average duration of notes (in seconds).</description>
      <is_sequential>true</is_sequential>
      <parallel_dimensions>1</parallel_dimensions>
   </feature>

   <feature>
      <name>Rhythmic Variability</name>
      <description>Standard deviation of the beat histogram bin magnitudes</description>
      <is_sequential>true</is_sequential>
      <parallel_dimensions>1</parallel_dimensions>
   </feature>

</feature_key_file>